<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All on Jasper Slingsby</title>
    <link>/tags/all/</link>
    <description>Recent content in All on Jasper Slingsby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/all/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought Monitor for the Jonkershoek Valley, Western Cape, South Africa</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-01-langrivier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-01-langrivier/</guid>
      <description>This analysis was prepared by the Fynbos Node of the South African Environmental Observation Network (SAEON).
Here we present the record of stream flow rates for the Langrivier catchment and rainfall from the Dwarsberg weather station in the Jonkershoek Valley for the period January 1961 to the end of August 2018. The Dwarsberg weather station is at 1214 metres above sea level on the boundary of the catchments of the Eerste, Berg and Sonderend rivers and is a good indicator of rainfall feeding the Berg and Theewaterskloof dams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIS and Landsat primer for Hannah</title>
      <link>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick primer on how to handle MODIS and Landsat NDVI data from Google Earth Engine (GEE) in R. It’s primarily for my Honours student, Hannah Simon, but I thought why not make it public for all to share? I first posted the MODIS section and had Hannah play with the Landsat data as a learning exercise, so full credit to her for the Landsat code.
For a general introduction for many of the functions used and handling spatial data in general see A Primer for Handling Spatial Data in R posted previously.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>