<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jasper Slingsby</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jasper Slingsby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought Monitor for the Jonkershoek Valley, Western Cape, South Africa</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-01-langrivier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-01-langrivier/</guid>
      <description>This analysis was prepared by the Fynbos Node of the South African Environmental Observation Network (SAEON).
Here we present the record of stream flow rates for the Langrivier catchment and rainfall from the Dwarsberg weather station in the Jonkershoek Valley for the period January 1961 to the end of April 2019. The Dwarsberg weather station is at 1214 metres above sea level on the boundary of the catchments of the Eerste, Berg and Sonderend rivers and is a good indicator of rainfall feeding the Berg and Theewaterskloof dams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The City of Cape Town&#39;s Draft Water Strategy - Inspirational? Aspirational? Or a poorly greenwashed status quo?</title>
      <link>/post/cape-town-draft-water-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cape-town-draft-water-strategy/</guid>
      <description>The City of Cape Town’s Draft Water Strategy is out for comment until the 15th March. This post provides a quick and opinionated précis of what it contains and the comments I’ve sent to the City. Even if you don’t agree with me, I encourage you to write to the City and have your say.
The Strategy in brief The document is structured around 5 “Commitments”, which are defined as “A willingness to give our time and energy to something that we believe in, a promise, a firm decision to do something”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #3. Big Data and Memory Management</title>
      <link>/post/big-spatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/big-spatial-data/</guid>
      <description>The Basics Interlude Doing GIS from R   Since I first started maintaining blog posts on handling spatial data in R perhaps the most common question I’ve received is “How do I handle big spatial data in R?”. I thought its finally time to provide a blog post to deal with this particular topic. The answer of course is that there are many, many ways.
Now I know those of you who have asked me in person are thinking “That’s not what he said when I asked?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #2. A practical example</title>
      <link>/post/spatial-data-in-r-2-a-practical-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spatial-data-in-r-2-a-practical-example/</guid>
      <description>A quick note on the structure of this tutorial Data Description Housekeeping Getting and cleaning the data, but first and foremost, projection!!! Let’s start with point data Raster data (mostly functions from library(raster)) Polygons! Going parallel!!! Animation! Some other data visualization and analysis But what about our poor cedars? Options for writing out spatial data   This post follows on from Handling Spatial Data in R - #1. Getting started, which gives the basics on installing R and RStudio, CRAN Spatial Task Views and useful DIY resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #1. Getting started</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-01-primerspatialdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-01-primerspatialdata/</guid>
      <description>Installing R (and RStudio) CRAN Spatial Task Views!!! Useful DIY resources   Points, lines, polygons and rasters - R can handle them all. My aim for this post is to give you the basics required to teach yourself spatial data analysis in R - following 3 major sections listed above.
In the next post I provide a practical example working with point, line, polygon and raster data. If you’re already familiar with R then you can skip straight there, but you may be interested to check out the useful DIY resources before you go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien VS Climate Change</title>
      <link>/post/alienvspredator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/alienvspredator/</guid>
      <description>The current drought experienced by Cape Town and surrounds has brought the issue of climate change to the fore in public discourse (if it wasn’t already). It’s discussed extensively in the media and plays a prominent role in the City’s Water Outlook 2018 Report (Version 25 - updated 20 May 2018) as motivation for the need for long term bulk water augmentation schemes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fire!!!</title>
      <link>/post/fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fire/</guid>
      <description>This is an updated quick and dirty analysis of the CapeNature fire database (spanning 1927 to 2017) to see if the major drought that is currently being experienced in the Cape Floristic Region has had any impact on the occurrence or extent of wildfires. I first ran this analysis exactly a year ago and I think you’ll find the new year’s worth of data quite interesting.
Wildfires are an essential component of fynbos, but components of the fire regime such as return interval need to be within certain bounds of variability to maintain healthy ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much water are we losing to alien trees?</title>
      <link>/post/aliens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aliens/</guid>
      <description>This post provides an interactive visualization of the results of Le Maitre et al. 2016. Estimates of the impacts of invasive alien plants on water flows in South Africa. Water SA Vol. 42 No. 4. It aims to highlight how much water could be reclaimed by clearing alien species from our catchments.
The extreme drought that is gripping Cape Town and surrounds has municipalities desperately seeking options to augment bulk water supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near-real time satellite monitoring of fynbos vegetation</title>
      <link>/post/emma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/emma/</guid>
      <description>Update! We submitted this project for the UN Global Pulse Data for Climate Action competition and won the Thematic Award for Climate Mitigation at COP23 in Bonn, Germany! :)
 Recent advances have seen the development of near-real time monitoring tools that report on the state and changes in vegetation based on satellite observations, e.g. globalforestwatch.org. These tools are hugely valuable for managing ecosystems and for developing the long term records required to understand ecosystem dynamics and trajectories of change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeldWatch!</title>
      <link>/post/veldwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/veldwatch/</guid>
      <description>This is just a very quick post to point out a Smartphone App I’ve been working on that allows citizen scientists, field rangers and landowners to map threats to and impacts on biodiversity. These include a range of impacts from invasive alien plants, plant mortality, landslides or illegal vegetation clearing, etc.
NOTE: Unfortunately, release of the app has been released due to location accuracy issues with the app development platform I’ve been using see this post for details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a citizen science App with the SAEON Graduate Student Network</title>
      <link>/post/gsn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gsn/</guid>
      <description>This is based on data collected when I took students from SAEON’s Graduate Student Network into the field to introduce them to Fynbos and to show them a bit of the science I’m working on. To make things more interesting, I got them to help me test a smartphone app I’ve been developing (“VeldWatch”) that can be used to map any impacts on natural ecosystems observed in the field, like invasive species, plant mortality, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans and forests in a changing sea of fire</title>
      <link>/post/fire-shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fire-shadows/</guid>
      <description>This is a study recently completed by one of my MSc students, Annabelle Rogers, who I co-supervised with Prof Ed February and Glenn Moncrieff. We’re busy writing it up for publication, but here’s a little preview.
The study was inspired by this great paper published by Dr Coert Geldenhuys in 1994, explaining how fire determines the distribution of forests in the Southern Cape. You can also read about it, and get a nice intro to our forests, in this interesting SA Forestry Online article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intensifying postfire weather and biological invasion drive species loss in fynbos</title>
      <link>/post/intensifying-postfire-weather-and-biological-invasion-drive-species-loss-in-fynbos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intensifying-postfire-weather-and-biological-invasion-drive-species-loss-in-fynbos/</guid>
      <description>After a decade of hard slog I finally had a study come out this week showing that increasingly prolonged periods of severe hot and dry weather during the first summer after wild fires is inhibiting vegetation recovery and causing loss of plant diversity in the Fynbos. If you don’t have access to the journal through the link above, I made a short video explaining the general gist.

Otherwise shoot me a message and I’ll send it to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIS and Landsat primer for Hannah</title>
      <link>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick primer on how to handle MODIS and Landsat NDVI data from Google Earth Engine (GEE) in R. It’s primarily for my Honours student, Hannah Simon, but I thought why not make it public for all to share? I first posted the MODIS section and had Hannah play with the Landsat data as a learning exercise, so full credit to her for the Landsat code.
For a general introduction for many of the functions used and handling spatial data in general see A Primer for Handling Spatial Data in R posted previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an ecologist based at the Fynbos Node of the South African Environmental Observation Network (SAEON), in Cape Town.
I created this (personal) site because it&amp;rsquo;s handy to be able to serve webpages for various applications and I got sick of having RPubs webpages floating all over the place.
I&amp;rsquo;m also considering using it as an Open Lab Book in the interests of supporting Open Notebook Science. There are many motivations for doing this, but primarily I believe that science should be fully transparent and repeatable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Papers and peer-reviewed book chapters 
 2019 Magadzire, N., de Klerk, H. M., Esler, K. J. and Slingsby, J. A. 2019. Fire and life history affect the distribution of plant species in a biodiversity hotspot. Diversity and Distributions; https://doi.org/10.1111/ddi.12921
 
2018 Poulos, H. M., Barton, A. M., Slingsby, J. A. and Bowman, D. M. J. S. 2018. Do Mixed Fire Regimes Shape Plant Flammability and Post-Fire Recovery Strategies?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>To summarize one&amp;rsquo;s research in a few short paragraphs is an impossible task, so please excuse the use of caveats and the general vagueness of this section. You&amp;rsquo;ll also note from my posts and publications that this is not an exhaustive list of my interests and activities. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to give a broad overview of the kinds of work I am currently doing and where I&amp;rsquo;d like to take them, but obviously there is a long list of ongoing projects that have rolled over from previous interests, collaborations and skills I have developed over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students</title>
      <link>/students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/students/</guid>
      <description>Current students PhD Nasiphi Ntshanga Nasiphi is doing her PhD with &amp;#x15E;erban Proche&amp;#351; and I, based at the School of Agricultural, Earth and Environmental Sciences, University of KwaZulu-Natal. Nasiphi is exploring the interactions between landscape transformation and other drivers of global change and their impacts on ecological processes and biodiversity in the Cape Floristic Region. Nasiphi is Chairperson of SAEON&amp;rsquo;s Graduate Student Network (GSN) and recently won the talk for best speaker at South Africa&amp;rsquo;s Third National Conference on Global Change in Durban in 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>