<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications copies on Jasper Slingsby</title>
    <link>/publications-copy/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications copies on Jasper Slingsby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2016 Your name or company</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:05:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/publications-copy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications-copy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;papers-and-peer-reviewed-book-chapters&#34;&gt;Papers and peer-reviewed book chapters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wigley, B. J., Slingsby, J. A., Díaz, S., Bond, W. J., Fritz, H. and Coetsee, C. 2016. Leaf traits of African woody savanna species across climate and soil fertility gradients: evidence for conservative vs. acquisitive resource use strategies. Journal of Ecology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiello-Lammens, M.E., Slingsby, J.A., Merow, C., Mollmann, H.K., Euston-Brown, D., Jones, C.S. &amp;amp; Silander Jr., J.A. 2016. Processes of community assembly in an environmentally heterogeneous, high biodiversity region. Ecography: pattern and diversity in ecology early view. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ecog.01945&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ecog.01945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verboom, G.A., Herron, M.L., Moncrieff, G.R and Slingsby, J.A. 2016. Maintenance of species integrity in the context of a recent radiation: the case of Jamesbrittenia (Scrophulariaceae: Limoselleae) in southern Africa. Botanical Journal of the Linnean Society, 2016, 182, 115–139&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daru, Barnabas H., Michelle van der Bank, Olivier Maurin, Kowiyou Yessoufou, Hanno Schaefer, Jasper A. Slingsby and T. Jonathan Davies. 2015. A novel phylogenetic regionalization of phytogeographic zones of southern Africa reveals their hidden evolutionary affinities. Journal of Biogeography 43: 155–166. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jbi.12619&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jbi.12619&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Molina-Venegas, R., Aparicio, A., Slingsby, J.A,;  Lavergne, S. &amp;amp; Arroyo, J. 2015. Investigating the evolutionary assembly of a Mediterranean biodiversity hotspot: deep phylogenetic signal in the distribution of eudicots across elevational belts. Journal of Biogeography 42:507-518. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jbi.12398&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jbi.12398&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moncrieff, G.R., Scheiter, S., Slingsby, J.A. &amp;amp; Higgins, S.I. 2015. Understanding global change impacts on South African biomes using Dynamic Vegetation Models. South African Journal of Botany 101: 16-23. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sajb.2015.02.004&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sajb.2015.02.004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seymour, C.L., Simmons, R.E., Joseph, G.S. &amp;amp; Slingsby, J.A. 2015. On bird functional diversity: species richness and functional differentiation show contrasting responses to rainfall and vegetation structure in an arid landscape. Ecosystems. 18: 971–984. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10021-015-9875-8&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10021-015-9875-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2014&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ackerly, D.D., Stock, W.D., Slingsby, J.A. 2014. Geography, Climate, and biodiversity: the history and future of Mediterranean-type ecosystems. In Allsopp, N., Colville, J.F. and Verboom, G.A.(editors), Fynbos: Ecology, Evolution and Conservation in a Megadiverse Region. Oxford University Press, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bouchenak-Khelladi, Y., Slingsby, J.A., Verboom, G. A. &amp;amp; Bond, W.J. 2014. Diversification of C4 grasses (Poaceae) does not coincide with their ecological dominance. American Journal of Botany 101:300-307. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.3732/ajb.1300439&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.3732/ajb.1300439&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moore, C., Cumming, G.S., Slingsby, J. &amp;amp; Grewar, J. 2014. Tracking socioeconomic vulnerability using network analysis: insights from an avian influenza outbreak in an ostrich production network. PlosONE 9:e86973. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0086973&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0086973&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slingsby, J.A., Britton, M.N. &amp;amp; Verboom, G.A. 2014. Ecology limits the diversity of the Cape flora: phylogenetics and diversification of the genus Tetraria. Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 72:61-70. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ympev.2013.11.017&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ympev.2013.11.017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slingsby, J.A., Ackerly, D.D., Latimer, A.M., Linder, H.P. &amp;amp; Pauw, A. 2014. The assembly and function of Cape plant communities in a changing world. In Allsopp, N., Colville, J.F. and Verboom, G.A.(editors), Fynbos: Ecology, Evolution and Conservation in a Megadiverse Region. Oxford University Press, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paxton, B.R., O’Brien, G.C., Slingsby, J.A. &amp;amp; Copin, R. 2013. Validation of the periodicity of growth increment deposition in otoliths from the larval and early juvenile stages of two cyprinids from the Orange–Vaal river system, South Africa. African Journal of Aquatic Science 38, Supplement 1:49-54. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.2989/16085914.2013.775107&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.2989/16085914.2013.775107&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valsecchi, V., Chase, B.M., Slingsby, J., Carr, A.S.; Quick, L.J., Meadows, M.E., Cheddadi, R. &amp;amp; Reimer, P.J. 2013. A high resolution 15,600-year pollen and microcharcoal record from the Cederberg Mountains, South Africa. Palaeogeography, Palaeoclimatology, Palaeoecology 387:6-16. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.palaeo.2013.07.009&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.palaeo.2013.07.009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viljoen, Jan-Adriaan; Muasya, A Muthama; Barrett, Russell L; Bruhl, Jeremy J; Gibbs, Adele K; Slingsby, Jasper A; Wilson, Karen L; Verboom, G Anthony. 2013. &amp;ldquo;Radiation and repeated transoceanic dispersal of Schoeneae (Cyperaceae) through the southern hemisphere&amp;rdquo;, American Journal of Botany, 100, 12, 2494-2508, Botanical Society of America&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2012&#34;&gt;2012&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schurr, F.M., Esler, K.J., Slingsby, J.A. &amp;amp; Allsopp, N. 2012. Fynbos Proteaceae as a model organism for biodiversity research and conservation. South African Journal of Science 108:10-13. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.4102/sajs.v108i11/12.1446&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.4102/sajs.v108i11/12.1446&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2007&#34;&gt;2007&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thuiller, Wilfried; Slingsby, Jasper A; Privett, Sean DJ; Cowling, Richard M. 2007. Stochastic species turnover and stable coexistence in a species-rich, fire-prone plant community. PloS One, 2, 9, e938, Public Library of Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2006&#34;&gt;2006&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slingsby, Jasper A; Verboom, G Anthony. 2006. Phylogenetic relatedness limits co‐occurrence at fine spatial scales: evidence from the Schoenoid sedges (Cyperaceae: Schoeneae) of the Cape Floristic Region, South Africa. The American Naturalist, 168, 1, 14-27, 2006&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-publications&#34;&gt;Other publications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slingsby, J.A., Slingsby, P.W.O. 2012. Mountain Fynbos &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; A World in One Cubic Foot: Portraits of Biodiversity. David Liittschwager. The University of Chicago Press, Chicago. 224 pages&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>