<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Tutorials on Jasper Slingsby</title>
    <link>/categories/r-tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Tutorials on Jasper Slingsby</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r-tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #3. Big Data and Memory Management</title>
      <link>/post/big-spatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/big-spatial-data/</guid>
      <description>The Basics Interlude Doing GIS from R   Since I first started maintaining blog posts on handling spatial data in R perhaps the most common question I’ve received is “How do I handle big spatial data in R?”. I thought its finally time to provide a blog post to deal with this particular topic. The answer of course is that there are many, many ways.
Now I know those of you who have asked me in person are thinking “That’s not what he said when I asked?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #2. A practical example</title>
      <link>/post/spatial-data-in-r-2-a-practical-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spatial-data-in-r-2-a-practical-example/</guid>
      <description>A quick note on the structure of this tutorial Data Description Housekeeping Getting and cleaning the data, but first and foremost, projection!!! Let’s start with point data Raster data (mostly functions from library(raster)) Polygons! Going parallel!!! Animation! Some other data visualization and analysis But what about our poor cedars? Options for writing out spatial data   This post follows on from Handling Spatial Data in R - #1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Spatial Data in R - #1. Getting started</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-01-primerspatialdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-01-primerspatialdata/</guid>
      <description>Installing R (and RStudio) CRAN Spatial Task Views!!! Useful DIY resources   Points, lines, polygons and rasters - R can handle them all. My aim for this post is to give you the basics required to teach yourself spatial data analysis in R - following 3 major sections listed above.
In the next post I provide a practical example working with point, line, polygon and raster data. If you’re already familiar with R then you can skip straight there, but you may be interested to check out the useful DIY resources before you go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a citizen science App with the SAEON Graduate Student Network</title>
      <link>/post/gsn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gsn/</guid>
      <description>This is based on data collected when I took students from SAEON’s Graduate Student Network into the field to introduce them to Fynbos and to show them a bit of the science I’m working on. To make things more interesting, I got them to help me test a smartphone app I’ve been developing (“VeldWatch”) that can be used to map any impacts on natural ecosystems observed in the field, like invasive species, plant mortality, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans and forests in a changing sea of fire</title>
      <link>/post/fire-shadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fire-shadows/</guid>
      <description>This is a study recently completed by one of my MSc students, Annabelle Rogers, who I co-supervised with Prof Ed February and Glenn Moncrieff. We’re busy writing it up for publication, but here’s a little preview.
The study was inspired by this great paper published by Dr Coert Geldenhuys in 1994, explaining how fire determines the distribution of forests in the Southern Cape. You can also read about it, and get a nice intro to our forests, in this interesting SA Forestry Online article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MODIS and Landsat primer for Hannah</title>
      <link>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modis-primer-for-hannah/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick primer on how to handle MODIS and Landsat NDVI data from Google Earth Engine (GEE) in R. It’s primarily for my Honours student, Hannah Simon, but I thought why not make it public for all to share? I first posted the MODIS section and had Hannah play with the Landsat data as a learning exercise, so full credit to her for the Landsat code.
For a general introduction for many of the functions used and handling spatial data in general see A Primer for Handling Spatial Data in R posted previously.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>